<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Openscapes</title>
    <link>/categories/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Openscapes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Personifying code</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/12/24/personify-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/12/24/personify-code/</guid>
      <description>Anything and everything we do to increase visibility of open practices and data science within environmental science communities is important. When we see things, it is easier to value them.
Openscapes Champion Allison Horst is doing this in part through her personifyr art series. She uses her art in the classroom at the University of California at Santa Barbara, where she is a lecturer of data science and statistics in an environmentally-focused graduate program, the Bren School of Environmental Science &amp;amp; Management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Openscapes</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/20/introducing-openscapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/20/introducing-openscapes/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on medium.com
I wrote this blog in preparation for MozFest — Mozilla’s annual festival for the open internet — October 2018, in London. I am a Mozilla Fellow, and I presented the idea of Openscapes, which will help increase the value of open practices within environmental science by engaging, empowering, and amplifying individuals.


As you know, we are currently facing some of the biggest environmental challenges of our time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start a coding club</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/16/how-to-start-a-coding-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/16/how-to-start-a-coding-club/</guid>
      <description>How to start a coding club Summary: start small, be hands-on, use existing tutorials, have fun.
Here is my advice for starting a coding club.
An example is Eco-Data-Science at UCSB. We are currently a community of &amp;gt;100 people; we meet 2x/month at the UCSB Library&amp;rsquo;s Collaboratory and skill share peer-to-peer, with all resources organized and archived on the website. But we started off small, with co-founder Jamie giving tutorials to friends one-on-one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Build communities</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/06/build-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/06/build-communities/</guid>
      <description>[Draft in progress!]
The Openscapes program is built with the idea that we can model the culture we want in academia. So what can you do?
What you can do as a grad student  read nature at journal club request swc workshop ask your Dept to teach data science courses seek out opportunities to learn, amplify join or start a study group/coding club [use Twitter for science]() join online communities, find allies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter for Community</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/10/09/twitter-for-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/10/09/twitter-for-community/</guid>
      <description>[coming soon!]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.rProfile Julia Stewart Lowndes</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/02/09/rprofile_lowndes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/02/09/rprofile_lowndes/</guid>
      <description>This interview was originally published by rOpenSci on February 9, 2018 as part of the .rprofile series.
[This interview occurred at the 2017 rOpenSci unconference]

SK: I’m Sean Kross, I’m the CTO of the Johns Hopkins Data Science Lab. Today I’m interviewing Julia Stewart Lowndes. Julia, what is your current preferred job title?
JSL: I’m calling myself a marine data scientist - I’m the Science Program Lead for the Ocean Health Index.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>