<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openscapes</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Openscapes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Personifying code</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/12/20/personify-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/12/20/personify-code/</guid>
      <description>Anything and everything we do to increase visibility of open practices and data science within environmental science communities is important. When we see things, it is easier to value them.
Openscapes Champion Allison Horst is doing this in part through her personifyr art series. She uses in the classroom at the University of California at Santa Barbara, where she is a lecturer of data science and statistics in an environmentally-focused graduate program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building communities</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/12/06/building-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/12/06/building-communities/</guid>
      <description> [To write!]
The Openscapes program is built with the idea that we can model the culture we want in academia. So what can you do?
What you can do as a grad student  read nature at journal club request swc workshop ask your Dept to teach data science courses seek out opportunities to learn, amplify join or start a study group/coding club  As faculty:  ask your Dept include funding for data in grant proposal give your students time space to learn this stufd  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start a coding club</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/24/how-to-start-a-coding-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/24/how-to-start-a-coding-club/</guid>
      <description>How to start a coding club Summary: start small, be hands-on, use existing tutorials, have fun.
Here is my advice for starting a coding club.
An example is Eco-Data-Science at UCSB. We are currently a community of &amp;gt;100 people; we meet 2x/month at the UCSB Library&amp;rsquo;s Collaboratory and skill share peer-to-peer, with all resources organized and archived on the website. But we started off small, with co-founder Jamie giving tutorials to friends one-on-one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Openscapes</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/20/introducing-openscapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/20/introducing-openscapes/</guid>
      <description>Cross-posted at medium.com
I wrote this blog in preparation for MozFest — Mozilla’s annual festival for the open internet — October 2018, in London. I am a Mozilla Fellow, and I presented the idea of Openscapes, which will help increase the value of open practices within environmental science by engaging, empowering, and amplifying individuals.
As you know, we are currently facing some of the biggest environmental challenges of our time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Champions Program</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/12/15/introducing-champions-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/12/15/introducing-champions-program/</guid>
      <description>[coming soon!]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter for Community</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/01/16/twitter-for-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/01/16/twitter-for-community/</guid>
      <description>[coming soon!]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Champions Program</title>
      <link>/champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/champions/</guid>
      <description>Openscapes Champions is a mentoring program for environmental scientists. We mentor early career researchers who are thought leaders in leadership roles. These scientists will become visible champions for open practices, and enable their lab groups to work openly.
The program is designed with the idea that scientific leaders can value and enable open practices, even before they become experts themselves. [reword!]

PURPOSE The purpose of the Champions program is to welcome more scientists to the open tools, practices, and communities that can accelerate their research and help us find environmental solutions faster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>VISION We can get to environmental solutions faster if we are more efficient and collaborative with how we do science.
HOW WE WORK We work openly and materials are available at github.com/openscapes. We are @openscapes on Twitter and Medium.
HOW TO GET INVOLVED There are many ways you can help build and strengthen communities at your institution.
Additionally, you are warmly invited to:
Amplify Openscapes &amp;amp; community efforts
 Join our community on twitter @openscapes Include the importance of open practices in your next talks and publications, and tell us about it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media and Presentations</title>
      <link>/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/media/</guid>
      <description> OPENSCAPES MEDIA OPENSCAPES PRESENTATIONS  slides  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>This page is under development and currently leverages previous work.
This is a curated list of resources to welcome environmental scientists to deliberately engage in and be empowered by open tools and communities. It is not meant to be comprehensive of all the incredible resources out there, but put together based trying to meet the needs of scientists following real conversations.

WORKING COLLABORATIVELY, OPENLY, &amp;amp; EFFICIENTLY Science is collaborative — you work daily with your most most important collaborator: Future You.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>