<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Openscapes</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Openscapes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Personifying code</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/12/30/personify-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/12/30/personify-code/</guid>
      <description>Anything and everything we do to increase visibility of open practices and data science within environmental science communities is important. When we see things, it is easier to value them.
Openscapes Champion Allison Horst is doing this in part through her personifyr art series. She uses her art in the classroom at the University of California at Santa Barbara, where she is a lecturer of data science and statistics in an environmentally-focused graduate program, the Bren School of Environmental Science &amp;amp; Management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Champions Program</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/12/21/introducing-champions-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/12/21/introducing-champions-program/</guid>
      <description>[coming soon!]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Openscapes</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/20/introducing-openscapes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/20/introducing-openscapes/</guid>
      <description>This article was originally published on medium.com
I wrote this blog in preparation for MozFest — Mozilla’s annual festival for the open internet — October 2018, in London. I am a Mozilla Fellow, and I presented the idea of Openscapes, which will help increase the value of open practices within environmental science by engaging, empowering, and amplifying individuals.


As you know, we are currently facing some of the biggest environmental challenges of our time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start a coding club</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/16/how-to-start-a-coding-club/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/16/how-to-start-a-coding-club/</guid>
      <description>How to start a coding club Summary: start small, be hands-on, use existing tutorials, have fun.
Here is my advice for starting a coding club.
An example is Eco-Data-Science at UCSB. We are currently a community of &amp;gt;100 people; we meet 2x/month at the UCSB Library&amp;rsquo;s Collaboratory and skill share peer-to-peer, with all resources organized and archived on the website. But we started off small, with co-founder Jamie giving tutorials to friends one-on-one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building communities</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/11/06/building-communities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/11/06/building-communities/</guid>
      <description>[Draft in progress!]
The Openscapes program is built with the idea that we can model the culture we want in academia. So what can you do?
What you can do as a grad student  read nature at journal club request swc workshop ask your Dept to teach data science courses seek out opportunities to learn, amplify join or start a study group/coding club [use Twitter for science]() join online communities, find allies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>.rProfile Julia Stewart Lowndes</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/02/09/rprofile_lowndes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/02/09/rprofile_lowndes/</guid>
      <description>This interview was originally published by rOpenSci on February 9, 2018 as part of the .rprofile series.
[This interview occurred at the 2017 rOpenSci unconference]

SK: I’m Sean Kross, I’m the CTO of the Johns Hopkins Data Science Lab. Today I’m interviewing Julia Stewart Lowndes. Julia, what is your current preferred job title?
JSL: I’m calling myself a marine data scientist - I’m the Science Program Lead for the Ocean Health Index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter for Community</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/01/16/twitter-for-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/01/16/twitter-for-community/</guid>
      <description>[coming soon!]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Openscapes is operated by the National Center for Ecological Analysis &amp;amp; Synthesis (NCEAS) and is being incubated by a Mozilla Fellowship awarded to Julia Stewart Lowndes.
VISION We can get to environmental solutions faster if we are more efficient and collaborative with how we do science.

ORIGIN STORY [draft!!]
All stories start somewhere. This story starts at [NCEAS](), a prestigeous ecology center that upcycles nad analyzes data to help solve enviromental challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Champions Program</title>
      <link>/champions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/champions/</guid>
      <description>Openscapes helps scientists become visible champions for open data science practices and promote them through their labs, teaching, and departments.
Openscapes Champions is a mentorship program for early career researchers in leadership roles (e.g. faculty, lecturers, program managers) that helps them become visible Champions for open practices. Since formal computing and data training are often not part of environmental education, Openscapes provides these emerging scientific leaders to have the opportunity to engage with existing open practices and guide their labs take the next steps appropriate for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Involved</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>HOW WE WORK We work openly and materials are available at github.com/openscapes. We are @openscapes on Twitter and Medium.
HOW TO GET INVOLVED There are many ways you can help build and strengthen communities at your institution.
Additionally, you are warmly invited to:
Amplify Openscapes &amp;amp; community efforts
 Join our community on Twitter Include the importance of open practices in your next talks and publications, and tell us about it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Media and Presentations</title>
      <link>/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/media/</guid>
      <description> OPENSCAPES MEDIA OPENSCAPES PRESENTATIONS  slides  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resources/</guid>
      <description>This page is under development and currently leverages previous work.
This is a curated list of resources to welcome environmental scientists to deliberately engage in and be empowered by open tools and communities. It is not meant to be comprehensive of all the incredible resources out there, but put together based trying to meet the needs of scientists following real conversations. 
WORKING COLLABORATIVELY, OPENLY, &amp;amp; EFFICIENTLY The scope of environmental research spans vastly different ecosystems, scales, and organisms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>